Guide to the Kiyoshi Koyama Papers MSS.598
Fales Library and Special Collections
Kiyoshi Koyama Papers
1967-2000
Fales Library and Special Collections
Koyama, Kiyoshi, 1936-2019
MSS.598
6.75 Linear Feet in 9 manuscript boxes and 3 record cartons.
78 sound cassettes (dat)
260 Cassettes
Kiyoshi Koyama (1936-2019) was a Japanese jazz journalist and producer. The Kiyoshi Koyama Papers contain notes and audio recordings of interviews conducted by Koyama with 20th century jazz musicians from 1967 to 2000. The collection also includes Koyama's research and recordings for Mercury Records releases, and personal calendars.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Kiyoshi Koyama, 2019. The accession number associated with this gift is 2020.016.
Appraisal
Personal scrapbooks, business correspondence, clippings, subject files on jazz musicians and jazz in media coverage, and playlists for Koyama's radio show were not retained. Mercury Records research and recordings may be re-appraised in the future.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by material type and subject. Notebooks and calendars are further arranged chronologically by year.
Biographical Note
Kiyoshi Koyama (1936-2019) was a Japanese jazz journalist and producer. He worked as the editor of Swing Journal from 1967 to 1981, and again from 1990 to 1993. Koyama also hosted a jazz radio show on NHK Radio 1 in Japan and, beginning in the early 1980s, produced box sets and anthologies of American jazz releases.
Custodial History
The Kiyoshi Koyama Papers were donated to NYU Special Collections in 2020. The archival collection was part of a larger donation that included Koyama's personal collection of commercially-released music, including LPs and CDs, and books and periodicals on jazz.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact NYU Special Collections, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
The Kiyoshi Koyama Papers date from 1967 to 2000 and contain notes and audio recordings of interviews conducted by Koyama with 20th century jazz musicians, presumably about the topic of jazz music. Interviewees include Sonny Rollins, the Marsalis Brothers, Miles Davis, Chick Corea, Ornette Coleman, Albert Ayler, Yamashita Yosuke, and Gil Evans. Research, including notes and audio recordings, on Mercury Records reissues and monthly calendars are also included. Notes are primarily in Japanese with limited English throughout.
Separated Materials
Books, periodicals, and commercial recordings (including LPs and CDs) from Koyama's personal collection are held by the Avery Fisher Center for Music and Media.
Jazz musicians -- Interviews; Jazz -- History; Interviews.
- Notebooks, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
- Notebooks, 1971-1980 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
- Notebooks, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
- Notebooks, 1983-1991 (Box 4, Folder 1-6)
- Notebooks, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
- Notebooks, 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
- Notebooks, 1996-1998 (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
- Notebooks, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
- Calendars, 1981-1992 (Box 8, Folder 1-5)
- Mercury Research, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
- Recorded Interviews, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 10)
- Mercury Research and Promo Sample Audio, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 11, Box 12)